Register of the A. (Andrei) Siniavskii Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1907-1999
  - Samizdat
    - General
      - Ideologiia i byt v tvorchestve Chekhova, n.d. (Folder 112: 6)
        Photo prints of handwritten text
      - "Poiski i razmyshleniia: Moskovskii obshchestvenno-literaturnyi zhurnal," nos. 6/14/, 1970's-1980's. (Folder 112: 7)
    - Andreev, Daniil, Gibel' Groznogo, n.d. (Folder 112: 8)
  - Sapgir, Genrikh. Miscellany, n.d. (Folder 112: 9)
  - Shakespeare, William. Russian translations of plays, n.d. (Folder 112: 10)
  - Shelkov, Vladimir, 1979.
    - Appeals to Amnesty International and others (Folder 112: 11)
    - Trial record (Folder 112: 12)
  - Shestalov, Ivan. "V Khelsinki," 1989. (Folder 112: 13)
  - Shragin, Boris. Writings., See also CORRESPONDENCE
    - General, 1983. (Folder 112: 14)
    - "Siniavskii: Abrama Tertsa," n.d. (Folder 112: 15)
  - Siniavskii, Egor. "Poluostrov," 1977. (Folder 112: 16)
  - Soiuz pisatelei RSFSR, "Zaivlenie," 1990. (Box-folder 113: 1)
  - Solomin, Vladimir. Announcements of lectures, 1966, and Sobesednik serdtsa: Etiudy o Pasternake, 1994. (Folder 113: 2)
  - Solovki (camp). Brochure, Solovetskie lageria osobogo naznacheniia 1923-1939, 1990 (Folder 113: 3)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr., See also PHOTOGRAPHS/ Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr
    - Clippings, including news releases, Radio Liberty Monitoring, 1975-1999 (Folder 113: 4-10)
    - Letters to the editor and open letters about Solzhenitsyn, 1974-1996. (Folder 113: 11)
    - Programs and publicity for conferences and films related to Solzhenitsyn, 1991-1998 (Box-folder 114: 1)
    - Radio programs
      - General, including BBC, 1979-1995 (Folder 114: 2)
      - Radio Liberty, 1975-1984., See also Radio Liberty/Transcripts of radio programs (Folder 114: 3)
    - Writings. Miscellany, 1975-1997. (Folder 114: 4)
      Printed matter
    - Writings about Solzhenitsyn
      - General, n.d. (Folder 114: 5)
      - Davydov, Oleg, "Kvadratura kruga ili chto zhe sobstvenno skazano v romane Solzhenitsyna," n.d. (Folder 114: 6)
      - Dunlop, John, "Solzhenitsyn: Unfinished Portrait," Problems of Communism, 1985. (Folder 114: 7)
      - Ianov, Aleksandr, "Na polputi k Leontievu: Paradoks Solzhenitsyna," n.d. (Folder 114: 8)
      - Kleipikova, Elena and Soloviev, Vladimir, "Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn: Golos iz nory," n.d. (Folder 114: 9)
      - Korotkov, A. et al, Kremlevskii samosud, 1994. (Folder 114: 10)
      - Losev, Lev, "S drugogo berega," 1984. (Folder 114: 11)
      - Medvedev, Roy, "Tvardovskii i Solzhenitsyn," 1976. (Folder 114: 12)
      - Navzorov, Lev, "Solzhenitsyn: A 'Prophet" of Freedom and Great Dissident or a Totalitarian? Solzhenitsyn: A Totalitarian of Stalin's Vintage," 1985. (Folder 114: 13)
      - Perakh, Mark, "Preklonenie pered faktami? Ili bor'ba s ten'iu Bershadera? Evrei i evreiskii vopros v tvorchestve Solzhenitsyna," 1973. (Folder 114: 14)
      - Petrov, Nikolai, "Pravda i nepravda Aleksandra Solzhenitsyna," n.d. (Folder 114: 15)
      - Proffer, Carl, "Solzhenitsyn: A Biography by Michael Scammel," The New Republic, 1984. (Folder 114: 16)
      - Referendum, "S kem teper' Solzhenitsyn?," 1990. (Folder 114: 17)
      - Reshetovskaia, Natalia, "Ot paskhi do Troitsy," n.d. (Folder 114: 18)
      - Sakharov, Andrei, "Otrytoe pis'mo," 1980. (Folder 114: 19)
      - Shragin, Vladimir, "Khomeinizm li?," n.d. (Folder 114: 20)
      - Tolstaia, Tatiana, untitled essay, n.d. (Folder 114: 21)
      - Tvardovskaia, V., "Otkrytoe pis'mo...," 1975. (Folder 114: 22)
  - "Sotsialist - 82," 1982. (Folder 114: 23)
  - Strana i Mir. Letter to Zinaida Shahovskaia, 1983 (Folder 114: 24)
  - Timofeev, Lev. Writings, n.d. (Folder 114: 25)
  - Tolkachev, V. Satires related to Andrei Siniavskii's and Mariia Rozanova's visit to Syzran', 1994. (Folder 114: 26)
  - Tribuna (Box 115)
    - General, 1983 (Folder 115: 1)
    - Belotserkovskii, Vadim, 1983-1986., See also SINTAKSIS FILE/Belotserkovskii, Vadim, and SUBJECT FILE/Belotserkovskii, Vadim (Folder 115: 2)
  - Udodov, Aleksandr. Miscellany, 1977 (Folder 115: 3)
  - Vishnevskaia, Iuliia. Writings, 1992. (Folder 115: 4)
  - Vladimov, Georgii. Miscellany, 1977-1986 (Folder 115: 5)
  - Voinovich, Vladimir, "Pisatel' na chuzhbine," 1985., See also Radio Liberty/Transcripts of radio programs (Folder 115: 6)
  - Vsesoiuznaia Tsrkov Vernykh i Svibodnykh Adventistov Sed'mogo Dnia. Miscellany, 1979. (Folder 115: 7)
  - Wat, Alexandre. Miscellaneous published material, 1963. (Folder 115: 8)
  - Zalkind, A., "O zabolevaniakh partaktiva," n.d. (Folder 115: 9)
  - Zamoyska, Hélène, "À propos de l'affaire Siniavski," draft of article for Le Monde, 1965. (Folder 115: 10)
  - Zholkovskii, Aleksandr. Miscellaneous articles, 1978-1993. (Folder 115: 11)
  - Zinoviev, Aleksandr. Clippings, 1984 (Folder 115: 12)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1916-1997
  - General. (Folder 115: 13-15)
    Printed matter with annotations by Andrei Siniavskii
  - General. (Folder 116: 1-6)
  - Books and journals, 1916-1996 (Folder 116: 7-8)
  - Books and journals, 1916-1996 (Box-folder 117: 1-2)
  - Leaflets and ephemera
    - Post-Soviet emigration in Paris, 1983-1996 (Folder 117: 3)
    - Russia
      - 1989-1990 (Folder 117: 4)
      - 1994-1996 (Folder 117: 5)
  - Newspaper issues and clippings
    - General
      - General (Folder 117: 6)
      - Dissidents, 1974-1978 (Folder 117: 7)
    - Soviet (Box 118)
      - General, 1930-1988 (Folder 118: 1)
      - Golos Rodiny, 1974-1976 (Folder 118: 2)
      - Za otlichnyi trud, 1969(camp newspaper) (Folder 118: 3)
    - Post-Soviet
      - Undated (Folder 118: 4)
      - 1989-1990 (Folder 118: 5)
      - 1991 (Folder 118: 6)
      - 1992 (Folder 118: 7)
      - 1993 (Folder 118: 8)
      - 1994
        - General (Folder 118: 9)
        - Gil'diia (Folder 118: 10)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 119: 1)
      - 1996-1997 (Folder 119: 2)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1890's-1993 (Box 120)
  - Aigi, Gennadii, 3 prints, n.d. (Folder 120: 1)
  - Amalrik, Andrei, n.d.
    - 2 prints depicting Andrei Amalrik and his wife Giuzel' and 1 print depicting Andrei Amalrik (Folder 120: 2)
    - 1 print depicting Grigorii Rasputin (Folder 120: 3)
  - Lege Artis Choir, St. Petersburg. 1 print depicting choir, 1991 (Folder 120: 4)
  - Levitin-Krasnov, Anatolii
    - 1 print depicting Nikolai Ivanov, 1989 (Folder 120: 5)
    - 2 prints depicting priest Aleksandr Kargon, 1977-1980 (Folder 120: 6)
    - 5 prints depicting Anatolii Levitin-Krasnov, 1975 (Folder 120: 7)
    - 1 portrait print depicting Mikhail Rodzianko and 2 prints depicting Bishop Vasilii (Rodzianko), n.d. (Folder 120: 8)
    - 1 portrait print depicting St. John of Kronstadt, n.d. (Folder 120: 9)
    - 1 print depicting an icon of St. Xenia of Petersburg, n.d. (Folder 120: 10)
    - 12 prints depicting Aleksandr Vvedenskii as priest and bishop, 1920-1943 (Folder 120: 11)
    - 1 print depicting Nikolai Zernov, n.d. (Folder 120: 12)
    - 3 postcards of Leningrad, n.d. (Folder 120: 13)
  - Pasternak, Boris. 1 print depicting Pasternak's funeral (Folder 120: 14)
  - Pasternak, Leonid. 3 prints of his paintings, sent to Siniavskii by Josephine Pasternak, 1983 (Folder 120: 15)
  - Pomerants, Grigorii. 1 print depicting Grigorii Pomerants and his wife, 1980 (Folder 120: 16)
  - Rogachev, Mikhail. 9 prints and 10 negatives depicting dedication of restored church in Russia, n.d. (Folder 120: 17)
  - Siniavskii, Andrei
    - 12 prints depicting the Siniavskii family, including Donat Siniavskii, Evdokiia Torkhova-Siniavskaia, and Andrei Siniavskii as an infant, 1917-1955 (Folder 120: 18)
    - 5 prints depicting Siniavskii as a high school student and student at Moscow State University, 1940's (Folder 120: 19)
    - 323 prints from trips to the Russian north, 1950's., See also OVERSIZE FILE/Photographs
      - 2 prints of Ferapontovo (Folder 120: 20)
      - 4 prints of Kii-Ostrov (Folder 120: 21)
      - 45 prints of the Mezen' River area (Folder 120: 22-23)
      - 2 prints of Novgorod (Folder 120: 24)
      - 2 prints of the Pechora River (Folder 120: 25)
      - 18 prints of the Pinega River. (Folder 120: 26)
        Includes print depicting Andrei Siniavskii and Mariia Rozanova
      - 25 prints of stone architecture (Folder 120: 27)
      - 39 prints of wooden church architecture (Folder 120: 28)
      - 127 prints of wooden village architecture and village scenes (Folder 120: 29-30)
      - 127 prints of wooden village architecture and village scenes (Box-folder 121: 1)
      - 57 prints representing peasant types and costumes (Folder 121: 2)
    - 8 prints depicting Siniavskii, 1955-1961 (Folder 121: 3)
    - 8 prints depicting Siniavskii and friends at Den'kovo, 1961-1962 (Folder 121: 4)
    - 3 prints from Siniavskii's dossier in the KGB archive, 1965 (Folder 121: 5)
    - 12 prints depicting Siniavskii in Zvenigorod, 1972. (Folder 121: 6)
      Includes group photographs with Iulii Daniel and other dissidents
    - 4 prints depicting Siniavskii in Moscow, including one with son Egor, 1971-1973 (Folder 121: 7)
    - 9 prints depicting Andrei Siniavskii, Mariia Rozanova, and Helene Zamoiska near Toulouse, 1973 (Folder 121: 8)
    - 11 portrait prints depicting Siniavskii, 1973-1991 (Folder 121: 9)
    - 26 prints depicting Siniavskii in group settings, 1974-1993 (Folder 121: 10)
    - 16 prints depicting award of Harvard honorary degree, 1991 (Folder 121: 11)
    - 1 print depicting the award of the Booker Russian Novel Prize to Siniavskii, 1992 (Folder 121: 12)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr. 1 print depicting Solzhenitsyn and his wife Natalia Reshetovskaia, n.d. (Folder 121: 13)
  - Temin, Gennadii. 2 prints, 1989 (Folder 121: 14)
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1970's-1993 (Box 122)
  - Phonotapes.
    Includes recordings of lectures, speeches, round-table discussions, radio broadcasts, and interviews with representatives of the third emigration
    - Agurskii, Mikhail
    - Aleshkovskii, Iuz
    - Amal'rik, Andrei
    - Aucouturier, Michel
    - Ben, Georgii
    - Blakely, Lucy
    - Corti, Mario
    - Dol'berg, Aleksandr
    - Fin'kel'shtein, Leonid
    - Friedberg, Maurice., See Kaganskaia, Maia (Box 123)
    - Friendly, Alfred
    - Galatskii, Vladimir
    - Golomshtok, Igor'
    - Glezer, Aleksandr
    - Ianov, Aleksandr
    - Kaganskaia, Maia
    - Kaganskaia, Maia (Box 124)
    - Khazanov, Boris
    - Khenkin, Kirill
    - Kuznetsov, Anatolii. Radio Liberty broadcasts entitled "Besedy Kuznetsova," 1973-1976 (Box 125)
    - Levitin-Krasnov, Anatolii and Andreev
    - Mak, Lev
    - Martinez, Louis
    - Nekrasov, Viktor (Box 126)
    - Rabin, Sam and Ira
    - Rapetti, S.
    - Reddaway, Peter, 1-2
    - Ronald, Francis
    - Rostropovich, Mstislav
    - Rubinshtein, Lev, "Nostalgiia," n.d. (Box 127)
    - Sapgir, Kira
    - Scammell, Michael
    - Sevela, Efrem
    - Sezeman, Dmitrii (Box 128)
    - Shariia, Nukzar
    - Shemiakin, Mikhail
    - Shtein, Emmanuel
    - Siniavskii, Andrei.
      Includes taping of A Voice From the Chorus for BBC Radio
    - Siniavskii, Andrei.
    - Siniavskii, Andrei. (Box 129)
    - Toskas, Ulrike
    - Veinshtein, Lev
    - Voronel', Nina
    - Voronel', Nina (Box 130)
    - Miscellany
  - Videotapes
    - Rozanova, Mariia. Interview on Russian television, n.d.
    - Siniavskii, Andrei. Program on the tenth anniversary of his emigration, 1993
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1900-1989 (Box 131)
  - Award, "Pokhval'nyii List," given to Evdokiia Torkhova Siniavskaia by the Syzran' Gymnasium, 1900
  - Honors
    - Bennett Award from The Hudson Review, 1978
    - Harvard University, Doctorate of Letters, 1991
    - International Freedom Prize, 1977
  - Lithographs
    - Kataoka, Miiko, n.d.
    - Le nouvel observateur, lithograph of magazine cover, 1994
  - Maps related to the Siniavskiis trips in the north Russian country-side, 1950's
  - Photographs
    - 1 portrait print depicting Andrei Siniavskii, n.d.
    - 2 prints related to the Siniavskii's and trips to the Russian north, 1950's
  - Posters (Map-case Map case)
    - Maiakovskii, Vladimir
      - Brigada po izucheniiu i propagande tvorchestva V. V. Maiakovskogo, 1946 and 1949.
        Announcement for poetry contest
      - Khudozhniki oformiteli proizvedenii Maiakovskogo, 1962.
        Program of exhibit
    - Public appearances of Andrei Siniavskii and Mariia Rozanova
      - Italy, 1977-1989
      - MGU Dom Kul'tury, n.d.
        Meeting of students with Mariia Rozanova